

User Experience Designer | Ul Engineer

yicaohci.com (650) 417 5279 @yidea email4yi@gmail.com 98 Church St. Apt. 6 Mountain View, CA 94041

QUALIFICATION HIGHLIGHT

User Experience Designer/Engineer with 3 years of experience in UX/UI Design and engineering. **Multi-Disciplined** academic background in **Human-Computer Interaction**, **Computer Science**, and **Fine Art**. UI work spans from Portal, Customer Support, Career Center, B2C, eNewsletter, Mobile sites and Search.

Expertise in **Semantic** HTML/CSS/jQuery/AJAX. Knowledge of technology trend and best practice in UI Design/Front-end, including Lean UX (**Rapid Prototyping** & Design Evaluation), **Usability**, Accessibility, Web Performance, and **SEO**. Ability to gauge design via **A/B test**, **Analytics** and **Usabiblity Test**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NetApp, Sunnyvale, CA *UX/UI Design Intern*

May 2011-Aug 2011

- + Practiced UCD process in redesigning Customer Support, Web Portal, and search
- + Translated user feedback and business requirements into Web/Mobile UI design
- + Prepared Wireframe (Visio), Prototypes (Axure), and Front-end (HTML/CSS/jQuery)
- + Validated and optimized design via A/B Test, Analytics, and Usability Testing
- + Documented Style Guide, Best Practice and conduct Web Performance
- + Worked closely with Dev and QA team to ensure the quality of UX/UI

BayCHI, Palo Alto, CA Web UI Designer Feb 2011-Present

- + Conducted user research, improved usability on registration, mobile and video
- + Created Wireframe, HTML Prototypes and Front end HTML5

Career Center, San Jose State University, CA Usability Engineer & Web UI Designer

Dec 2010-May 2011

- + Gauged the Accessibility (Section508) and Usability of sites, employed A/B test and usability test to optimize design
- + Designed usable and aesthetic UI, and strived for UI consistency and best practice
- + Implemented UI using HTML/CSS/jQuery, and checked browser compatibility

Taproot Foundation, San Francisco, CA Web UI Designer & Front End

Sep 2010-May 2011

- + Worked collaboratively with a team of 6 on Design Research
- + Designed and Implemented standard and semantic HTML/CSS/JS UI

Freelance Web UI Designer & Developer, New York, NY

Dec 2008-Aug 2010

- + Translated user feedback and business requirements into Web/Mobile UI design
- + Designed clean, elegant and accessible UI and prepared wireframe and prototypes
- + Implemented standard HTML/CSS/JS interface on PHP Codeigniter MVC

Hamkoo Information Technology LTD., China

Sep 2007-Sep 2008

Front end Engineer

+ Implemented web UI using HTML/CSS/JS on PHP/.Net /Java MVC framework

TRAINING

Web Usability (Jakob Nielsen)
Mobile User Experience (Raluca Budiu)
Ul Design Principle (Kathryn Whitenton)
Remote Usability Testing (Tom Tullis)
Fine Art (6 years)

Usability Week 2010, SF Usability Week 2010, SF

Usability Week 2010, SF

HFES 2010 Annual meeting, SF 2000, China

EDUCATION

M.S. HCI / Human Factor San Jose State University

Aug 2010-May 2012 (Expected)

M.S. Coursework in Management Information Systems **Dalian Maritime University**

Oct 2008

B.S. in Management Information Systems **Dalian Maritime University**

May 2007